<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on The Gauntlet: An R Blog</title>
    <link>https://mikegaunt404.netlify.app/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on The Gauntlet: An R Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mikegaunt404.netlify.app/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Organized Code</title>
      <link>https://mikegaunt404.netlify.app/2024/10/02/clean-structured-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikegaunt404.netlify.app/2024/10/02/clean-structured-code/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis vignette explains why using a consistent script structure and metadata format is essential for collaboration, efficiency, and reproducibility in R projects. By following a standardized template, you ensure that anyone using your scripts can quickly understand what the script does, who created it, and any specific requirements needed to run it.
By the end of this vignette, you’ll be familiar with a script template that helps organize code effectively and facilitates rapid development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean that Code up with purrr</title>
      <link>https://mikegaunt404.netlify.app/2023/10/02/purrr-correlation-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mikegaunt404.netlify.app/2023/10/02/purrr-correlation-plots/</guid>
      <description>This blog serves as a brief tutorial on how to utilize the purrr package by our studio to streamline and simplify complex or repetitive sections of code.
BackgroundOne major advantage of working with us is the ability to leverage the power of the Tidyverse R package environment. This package environment, developed by RStudio, is designed to enhance the usability of R.
An example of this enhancement is the use of ggplot for creating plots in R, as opposed to base R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
